<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Sts Assume-Role on Today I Learned</title><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/tags/sts-assume-role/</link><description>Recent content in Sts Assume-Role on Today I Learned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://skalt.github.io/til/tags/sts-assume-role/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/30/</guid><description>&lt;p>That the max duration for any AWS assumed role session is 12h.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>--duration-seconds (integer)
The duration, in seconds, of the role session. The value specified can range from 900 seconds (15 minutes) up to the maximum session duration set for the role. **The maximum session duration setting can have a value from 1 hour to 12 hours.** If you specify a value higher than this setting or the administrator setting (whichever is lower), the operation fails. For example, if you specify a session duration of 12 hours, but your administrator set the maximum session duration to 6 hours, your operation fails.
Role chaining limits your Amazon Web Services CLI or Amazon Web Services API role session to a maximum of one hour. When you use the AssumeRole API operation to assume a role, you can specify the duration of your role session with the DurationSeconds parameter. You can specify a parameter value of up to 43200 seconds (12 hours), depending on the maximum session duration setting for your role. However, if you assume a role using role chaining and provide a DurationSeconds parameter value greater than one hour, the operation fails. To learn how to view the maximum value for your role, see View the Maximum Session Duration Setting for a Role in the IAM User Guide .
By default, the value is set to 3600 seconds.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>see &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/sts/assume-role.html#options">https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/sts/assume-role.html#options&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>