<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Aws on Today I Learned</title><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/tags/aws/</link><description>Recent content in Aws on Today I Learned</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC BY-NC-SA 4.0</copyright><atom:link href="https://skalt.github.io/til/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/02/28/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/02/28/</guid><description>If you want to get a list of aws:principalTags/* values that can be used in your IAM conditions, search CloudTrail events for Event Name: AssumeRoleWithSaml.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/05/03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/05/03/</guid><description>aws policy documents can change the order of items within permissions arrays, but that&amp;rsquo;s safe to ignore:
Order is lost for data aws_iam_policy_document Policy elements that are syntactically lists but semantically sets should have their order ignored Perpetual diffs / Objects have changed outside of Terraform tracking ticket Also, that &amp;amp; types take 8 bytes = 64 bits on 64-bit systems
use std::mem; pub struct Foo { bar: String, // 24 baz: usize, // 8 } pub struct Quux&amp;lt;&amp;#39;a&amp;gt; { foo: &amp;amp;&amp;#39;a Foo, bar: usize, } fn main() { println!</description></item><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/22/</guid><description>About IfExists AWS IAM conditions: if a condition key might not exist (the resource doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it built-in, or a tag isn&amp;rsquo;t set), you can append IfExists to the condition test. For example StringEquals -&amp;gt; StringEqualsIfExists.
See https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/reference_policies_elements_condition_operators.html#Conditions_IfExists</description></item><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/08/30/</guid><description>That the max duration for any AWS assumed role session is 12h.
--duration-seconds (integer) The duration, in seconds, of the role session. The value specified can range from 900 seconds (15 minutes) up to the maximum session duration set for the role. **The maximum session duration setting can have a value from 1 hour to 12 hours.** If you specify a value higher than this setting or the administrator setting (whichever is lower), the operation fails.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/11/07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/11/07/</guid><description>that AWS ALB target groups support HTTPS healthcheck targets: https://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticloadbalancing/latest/application/target-group-health-checks.html
That FQDN stands for Fully Qualified Domain Name. For example sub.domain.tld. is a FQDN.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/11/08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://skalt.github.io/til/2022/11/08/</guid><description>That the aws_ec2_tag resource can be used to add tags to AWS RAM-shared VPCs and subnets:
This resource should only be used in cases where EC2 resources are created outside Terraform (e.g., AMIs), being shared via Resource Access Manager (RAM), or implicitly created by other means (e.g., Transit Gateway VPN Attachments).
Also, that
When the source of a module is a version control repository or archive file (generically, a &amp;ldquo;package&amp;rdquo;), the module itself may be in a sub-directory relative to the root of the package.</description></item></channel></rss>